Burlingame Family Papers
Burlingame Family Papers
1821-1967
Burlingame family.
34 linear ft.
Correspondence, incoming and outgoing (1856-1967); legal and financial records; memorabilia, including address books, clippings, genealogical records, and photographs; and writings, mostly of Roger Burlingame, including manuscript and/or published articles, books, book reviews, diaries, poems, short stories, and speeches. Family members represented include Anson Burlingame (1820-1870), a politician and diplomat; Edward L. Burlingame (1848-1922), author and editor; William Roger Burlingame (1889-1967), author, biographer, and novelist; and his wife, Angeline Whiton (d. 1967), a literary agent, known professionally as Ann Watkins. Notable correspondents include authors, poets, artists, etc.
148877
Biographical History
Three generations of the Burlingame family are represented in the papers of this collection. The three major historical figures in the family are discussed below in accordance with the amount of material present on each individual.
Anson Burlingame (1820-1870) was the son of Joel and his wife Freelove (Angell) Burlingame. He attended the University of Michigan and Harvard Law School. After marriage to Jane Cornelia Livermore, the daughter of Isaac Livermore, Burlingame began a promising political career in the Massachusetts Senate. In 1855 he was elected as a Republican to Congress where he served three terms. After the presidential campaign of 1860 he became minister to Peking in which capacity he concluded the Burlingame Treaty. He and his wife, Jane Cornelia Livermore, had three children: Edward Livermore (b. 1848), Walter Angell (b. 1852), and Gertrude (1853-?). Burlingame died while on a diplomatic mission to St. Petersburg, Russia in 1870.
Edward Livermore Burlingame (1848-1922), also known as E.L. Burlingame, was Jane and Anson's eldest son. As a young man he grew up in the Cambridge, Massachusetts area, and in 1861 entered Harvard. When his father was appointed minister to China, young Edward followed him to Peking, and later Paris, Berlin, Heidelberg, and St. Petersburg. In 1871 he began a career with the New York Tribune, and married Ella Frances Badger in the same year. He and his wife had four children: Jane (b. 1872), Frederick Anson (b, 1873), Constance (b. 1877), and William Roger (b. 1889). Burlingame became a literary advisor to Charles Scribner's Sons, and in 1886 was appointed editor of the new Scribner's Magazine, a post he held until his resignation in 1914.
William Roger Burlingame (1889-1967), known as Rog or Roger, was the second son of Edward and Ella Burlingame. As a boy Roger attended Morristown School and went on to Harvard University, graduating from the latter in 1913. After serving with the American Expeditionary Force in France during World War I, he returned to America and assumed various posts with Charles Scribner's Sons. In 1926 he began a career as a free-lance writer augmented by teaching stints at Barnard and M.I.T. During the course of his long career, Burlingame wrote articles, essays, books, and short stories. He is particularly known for non-fiction works on the historical impact of industry and technology on American society, though he did publish several novels during the early part of his career. His autobiography, published in 1958, is entitled I Have Known Many Words. In 1933 Roger married Angeline Whiton, known professionally as Ann Watkins, literary agent and president of Ann Watkins Inc. Mr. and Mrs. Burlingame died within a few days of each other in 1967.
A genealogical chart of the Burlingame family is available at the end of this inventory.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Burlingame Family Papers consists of the private and public papers of several generations of the prominent American family. The major contributor to the collection is writer and historian Roger Burlingame. There are also small amounts of material relating to Anson, Walter A., Edward Livermore, and Ann Burlingame. The papers are organized in five major groups: Correspondence, Legal and Financial Records, Memorabilia, Organization Records, and Writings.
Correspondence is separated into incoming, family, and outgoing letters. Among the items of special interest are the letters written by Walter A. Burlingame describing his experiences in China while accompanying his father, ambassador Anson Burlingame, in 1866 and 1867. Also present are letters from well known authors including F. Scott Fitzgerald, John Marquand, Edith Wharton, Roald Dahl, Ayn Rand, Tasha Tudor, Rudyard Kipling, Archibald MacLeish, Kaye Boyle, Sidney Howard, and others.
Legal and Financial Records contains documents pertinent to the-business affairs of several family members. There are wills, insurance policies, passports, royalty statements, and a variety of materials of a similar nature.
Memorabilia, dating from 1865 to 1967, contains items of incidental interest about the private lives of the Burlingame and related families. Included in this group are address books, newspaper clippings, ephemera, genealogical records, biographical material, and photographs.
Organization records consist of materials related to Roger Burlingame's association with various organizations. Among these are the Century Club, the Housatonic Valley Conference, Office of War Information, and the United States Army. Many of these organizations are also represented in Correspondence, above.
Writings date from 1856 to 1967, and include the written works of Roger, Ann, Walter, and Anson Burlingame. The bulk of this material was prepared by Roger Burlingame and includes articles, books, book reviews, diaries, poetry, short stories, and speeches. Included in this group are drafts of published and unpublished works as well as materials used in preparing the drafts. There is a miscellany of literary works and drawings done by others.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming letters are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the sender or by the name of the institution the sender represents; a small amount of incoming correspondence to Walter Burlingame is foldered separately at the end of this section. Family correspondence is arranged roughly chronologically. Outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically by year and month; a small anount of unsorted outgoing correspondence has been placed at the beginning of this section. Memorabilia is organized alphabetically by type of material. Manuscript materials are organized alphabetically by the name of the organization, and subdivided by the type of document. Writings are arranged alphabetically by author, and then by type of written work.
Note that due to rearrangement of the files there is NO BOX 14.
Related Material
Several items have been removed from the collection and sent to Rare Books.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Bacon, Leonard.; Beatty, Hetty Burlingame.; Boyle, Kay, 1902-1992.; Burlingame, Anson, 1820-1870.; Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore), 1848-1922.; Burlingame, Roger, 1889-1967.; Davis, Elmer, 1890-1958.; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970.; Dulles, Allen, 1893-1969.; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985.; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Goodman, Nathan G. (Nathan Gerson), 1899-; Howard, Sidney Coe, 1891-1939.; James, Henry, 1843-1916.; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1893-1960.; Murrow, Edward R.; Osborne, Lithgow, 1892-1980.; Pringle, Henry F. (Henry Fowles), 1897-1958.; Roper, Elmo, 1900-1971.; Shirer, William L. (William Lawrence), 1904-1993.; Thurber, James, 1894-1961.; Watkins, Ann, 1885-1967.; Wharton, Edith, 1862-1937.; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-1985.; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; Burlingame family.; Authors, American.; Biographers -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Literary agents.; Address books.; Appointment books.; Articles.; Book reviews.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Genealogies (histories); Manuscripts for publication.; Obituaries.; Photographs.; Poems.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Biographers.; Literary agents.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Abb - Aut, 1888-1967; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Agar, Herbert, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Angell, James B., 1888 (Box 1)
    - Angell, Malcolm H., 1888-1901 (Box 1)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1933-1959 (Box 1)
    - Bab - Byr, 1904-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Baber, E. Colborne, 1867 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1947-1953 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Martha (Box 1)
    - Barrie, J.M., 1895-1933 (Box 1)
    - Bishop, Joseph Bucklin, 1922; 1927 (Box 1)
    - Black, John, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Bok, Edward W., 1922 (Box 1)
    - Bouché, Louis and Marian, 1953; 1961,; 1965,; undated (Box 1)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1935-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Brown, John, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Brush, Katherine, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Burt, Maxwell Struthers, 1926-1949 (Box 1)
    - Cai - Chas, 1897-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Che-Cu, 1897-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Canby, Henry S., 1948-1950 (Box 2)
    - Cane, Melville, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Carmer, Carl, 1951-1965 (Box 2)
    - Clapp, Fred M., 1965 (Box 2)
    - The Century Association, 1938-1967; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - City Bank Farmers Trust Co., 1939-1946 (Box 2)
    - Coleman, Roy V. (Box 2)
    - Copeland, Charles T., 1935 (Box 2)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Coward-McCann Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 2)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 2)
    - Crothers, Rachel (Box 2)
    - Dal - Dyk, 1922-1966; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Dahl, Roald (Box 2)
    - Dana, Richard H., 1959 (Box 2)
    - Davis, Elmer, 1940-1953 (Box 2)
    - Dos Passos, John, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Doubleday & Co., 1934-1961 (Box 2)
    - Dulles, Allen W., 1965 (Box 2)
    - Ear - Ewi, 1922-1966 (Box 2)
    - Eaton, Evelyn, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Edmunds, Walter D., 1936 (Box 2)
    - Eisenhower, Milton S., 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - Fal - Fus, 1868-1965; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davidson, 1936 (Box 3)
    - Field, Leslie A., 1955 (Box 3)
    - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1924-1935 (Box 3)
    - The Forum, 1926-1938 (Box 3)
    - Gab - Gut, 1885-1966; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth [MISSING 1/25/19], 1966 (Box 3)
    - Goodman, Nathan G., 1938-1949 (Box 3)
    - Hal - Hus, 1892-1966; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Harcourt, Alfred, 1936-1958 (Box 3)
    - Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1938-1946; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1927; 1962 (Box 3)
    - Harvard, 1910-1960; includes letter from Dean regarding William Burlingame's grades (Box 3)
    - Histon, Timothy G., 1919-1922 (Box 3)
    - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1943 (Box 3)
    - Howard, Clare, 1925 (Box 3)
    - Howard, Polly, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
    - Howard, Sidney, 1924-1936 (Box 3)
    - Imp - Joy, 1929-1966 (Box 3)
    - The Independent, 1913 (Box 3)
    - James, Henry, 1892 (Box 3)
    - James, William (painter) [MISSING 1/25/19], 1891 (Box 3)
    - Jones, Bassett, 1954-1956 (Box 4)
    - Jones, Bassett, 1956-1959 (Box 4)
    - Kai - Kuh, 1866-1966; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Kieffer, Paul, 1951-1967 (Box 4)
    - Kipling, Rudyard, 1897 (Box 4)
    - [Alfred A.] Knopf Inc., 1946-1964; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Lab - Lyo, 1886-1966; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Leavitt, Robert Keith, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
    - Library of Congress, 1937-1963 (Box 4)
    - Linderman, Frank Bird, 1934 (Box 4)
    - [J.B.] Lippincott Co., 1959-1964; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Littauer, Kenneth (Littauer & Wilkinson), 1946-1964 (Box 5)
    - Littell, Robert (Box 5)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1917 (Box 5)
    - Low, Will Hicock, 1922 (Box 5)
    - Maa - Mye, 1868-1967; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1952-1964 (Box 5)
    - The MacMillan Co., 1932-1967 (Box 5)
    - Mannhardt, [Emil?], 1883-1889 (Box 5)
    - Manship, Paul, 1945; 1966 (Box 5)
    - Marquand, John and Mrs., 1924-1967 (Box 5)
    - Martin, Edward S., 1932 (Box 5)
    - McCormick, Jay, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
    - McGraw-Hill Publishing Co., Inc., 1952-1967 (Box 5)
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1959 (Box 5)
    - Nad - Nye, 1933-1964; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1940-1962 (Box 5)
    - The New American Library of World Literature, Inc., 1952-1967 (Box 5)
    - Oak - Oye, 1924-1967 (Box 5)
    - Osborne, Lithgow, 1954-1967 (Box 5)
    - Pag - Pyn, 1870-1967; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Perkins, Maxwell, 1928 (Box 6)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1924 (Box 6)
    - Pringle, Henry F., 1948-1950 (Box 6)
    - Rad - Rut, 1911-1967; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1937 (Box 6)
    - Reid, Whitelaw, 1872; 1962; may be father and son (Box 6)
    - Rhodes, James F., 1922 (Box 6)
    - Roos, Barney, Frances and Delmar, 1938-1961 (Box 6)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1961; reproduction; letter from ER to a Miss Helland, about Roger Burlingame's book Don't Let Them Scare You (Box 6)
    - Roper, Elmo, 1952-1964 (Box 6)
    - Sab - Syr, 1916-1966; 8 folders (Box 7)
    - [Charles] Scribner's Sons, 1929-1967 (Box 7)
    - Seager, Allan, 1950-1964 (Box 7)
    - Shepardson, Whitney H., 1952-1966 (Box 7)
    - Sherwood, Robert E. (Box 7)
    - Shirer, William L., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Sons of the Revolution, 1897; 1923-1924 (Box 7)
    - Spillane, Mickey (Box 7)
    - Stone, Grace, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Streeter, Edward, 1930-1962 (Box 7)
    - Taf - Two, 1910-1966; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Taylor, Bayard, 1877 (Box 7)
    - Thompson, Francis, 1917 (Box 7)
    - Thurber, James, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Tudor, Tasha and Rosamond [her mother], 1935-1938 (Box 7)
    - Und - Ust, 1919-1962 (Box 7)
    - United States Information Agency, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
    - United States Patent Office, 1910 (Box 7)
    - Vai - Vol, 1924-1966 (Box 7)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1944 (Box 7)
    - The Viking Press, Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 7)
    - Wal - Wyn, 1869-1965; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Watkins, Ann [later Ann Burlngame], 1914-1923 (Box 7)
      See also Correspondence: Family: Roger and Ann.
    - Wharton, Edith, 1914; 1922 (Box 7)
    - White, E.B., 1960 (Box 7)
    - Whitney, Hetty, 1960-1966 (Box 7)
    - Whiton, Louis, 1944-1965 (Box 7)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Winchester Repeating Arms Company, 1936-1944; mostly Edwin Pugsley (Box 8)
    - Yal - Zer, 1937-1965 (Box 8)
    - Incoming to Walter Burlingame [330-348], 1868-1895; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Unidentified, 1909-1965; first name only, no name, illegible name; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Family
    Family correspondence is arranged chronologically, with names where applicable. Family members represented include Anson Burlingame, Edward Livermore Burlingame, William Roger Burlingame and his sisters, and various aunts, uncles, cousins, etc. Some of the letters are numbered, due to having once been cataloged.
    - Family [320, #1-19, plus a few unnumbered items], 1852-1866; mostly Walter Burlingame to mother (Box 8)
    - Family [320, #20-34], 1866-1867; mostly Walter Burlingame to mother (Box 8)
    - Family [#329, #1-22], 1866-1873; from Gertrude (Gertie) (Box 8)
    - Family [320, #35-59], 1868; mostly Walter Burlingame to mother or "Grandpa"; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Family, 1868; from Walter Burlingame to "Grandpa," appear to relate to trip to Middle East (Box 10B)
    - Family [328, #1-19], 1868 Mar-1869 Jun; from Edward Livermore Burlingame (Box 8)
    - Family [320, #60-80], 1869; mostly Walter Burlingame to mother; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Family [320, #81-101], 1870; 2 folders (Box 9A)
    - Family [321, #102-107; 322, #108-128; 323, #129-135], 1871; 3 folders (Box 9A)
    - Family [324, #136-155], 1872 (Box 9A)
    - Family [325, #156-178], 1873; 2 folders (Box 9A)
    - Family [326, #179-192], 1874; 2 folders (Box 9A)
    - Family [327, #193-204], 1875; 2 folders (Box 9A)
    - Family, 1883-1915 (Box 9A)
    - Roger Burlingame and sisters, 1916-1919 (Box 9A)
    - Roger and E. L. Burlingame, 1916-1921 (Box 9A)
    - Family, 1916 Jun-Dec; mostly Roger Burlingame to mother Ella; 2 folders (Box 9B)
    - Family, 1917; Roger Burlingame to mother Ella; 3 folders (Box 9B)
    - Family, 1917; Roger Burlingame from mother Ella (Box 9B)
    - Family, 1918; Roger Burlingame to mother Ella; 2 folders (Box 9B)
    - Family, 1918; Roger Burlingame from mother Ella (Box 9B)
    - Family, 1919; Roger Burlingame to mother Ella (Box 10)
    - Family, 1919-1927; Roger Burlingame from mother Ella (Box 10)
    - Roger and Ann Watkins (his wife), 1919-1951 (Box 10)
      See also Correspondence: Incoming: Watkins, Ann.
    - Roger and Ann Watkins (his wife), undated (Box 10A)
    - Miscellaneous family, undated, senders include Roger, Walter, Bert, Roderick S., Anson, Hetty, Ludie, "Uncle George" and "Cousin Laura" (Box 10A)
    - Miscellaneous postcards, 1909-1965; most from Europe (Box 10A)
  - Outgoing
    - Miscellaneous, unsorted, some dated, some undated; 2 folders (Box 10A)
    - [General], 1934 Mar-1937 Dec (Box 11)
    - [General], 1938; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1939 (Box 11)
    - [General], 1940 (Box 11)
    - [General], 1941; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1942 Feb-1944 Dec (Box 11)
    - [General], 1945 (Box 11)
    - [General], 1946; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1947 Jan-1948 Oct; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1949; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1952 Jan-1957 Dec; 6 folders (Box 12)
    - [General], 1958 Jan-Nov; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - [General], 1959; 6 folders (Box 12)
    - [General], 1960; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - [General], 1961; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - [General], 1962 Jan-1967 Mar; 6 folders (Box 13)
- Legal and financial
  - Miscellaneous, 1885-1919 (Box 13)
  - Accounts, 1877-1949 (Box 13)
  - Birth, confirmation, and marriage certificates, 1889-1933 (Box 13)
  - Bonds, 1939 (Box 13)
  - Cemetery deeds, 1888-1944 (Box 13)
  - Contracts and agreements, 1910-1961; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Copyrights, 1930-1956 (Box 13)
  - Deeds, 1945 (Box 13)
  - Estates and wills
    - Burlingame, Ella F., 1927 (Box 15)
    - Burlingame, Roger and Ann, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Flanders, Delia, 1913 (Box 15)
  - Interest statements, 1939-1944 (Box 15)
  - Insurance policies
    - Burlingame, Edward Livermore, 1876-1886 (Box 15)
    - Burlingame, Roger and Ann, 1885-1941 (Box 15)
  - Leases
    - Burlingame, Ann, 1945-1948 (Box 15)
    - Burlingame, Edward Livermore, 1871-1889 (Box 15)
  - Mortgages, 1937-1952; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Passports, 1870-1937 (Box 15)
  - Power of attorney, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Royalties, 1924-1953; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Royalties, 1954-1967; 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Social Security Information, 1951-1961 (Box 16)
  - Stock certificates, 1939 (Box 16)
- Memorabilia
  - Account and note books, circa 1918; undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Address and appointment books, 1925-1965; undated; 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Autograph books, 1929-1933 (Box 18)
  - Biographical material
    - Burlingame, Anson, undated (Box 18)
    - Burlingame, Edward Livermore, circa 1905 (Box 18)
    - Burlingame, Frederic A., circa 1937 (Box 18)
    - Burlingame, Roger, undated (Box 18)
  - Book publicity, for intermediate readers by Roger Burlingame; typescript carbon (Box 18)
  - Childhood projects
    - "Cazenovia Model Yacht Co.", 1904; handwritten and illustrated catalogs, with prices (Box 18)
    - "Hienya Cyerra Tenaller", circa 1903; very short play about pirates (Box 18)
    - "Long Mass Magazine", circa 1899-1903; handwritten; poetry, illustrations, etc.; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - "The Story of a Horse", circa 1895; handwritten and illustrated story, dedicate to sister Constance (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1903 (Box 18)
  - Clippings, 1821-1956; undated; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Ephemera, 1856-1918 (Box 18)
  - Garden record books, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Genealogical records
    - Burlingame family, 1946-1947; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Kingsley family, 1837-1902 (Box 18)
    - Whiton family, 1908-1962 (Box 18)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship application, 1940 (Box 19)
  - Lists, undated (Box 19)
  - Medical records, 1909-1961 (Box 19)
  - Memory books, circa 1905 (Box 19)
  - Party lists and invitations, undated (Box 19)
  - Photographs
    - Badger family, circa 1880-1890 (Box 19)
    - Burlingame, Ann, 1885-1904; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Burlingame, Ann, 1908-1965; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Burlingame, Anson, circa 1865 (Box 20)
    - Burlingame, Edward Livermore, circa 1850-1920 (Box 20)
    - Burlingame, Ella, circa 1870-1874 (Box 20)
    - Burlingame family and friends, 1850-1940; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Burlingame, Roger, 1895-1967; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Burlingame, Roger House, 1950-1965 (Box 22)
    - Clemens, Samuel L. (autographed), 1870-1909 (Box 22)
    - Howard, Sidney, 1935 (Box 22)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (autographed), undated (Box 22)
    - Hopin family, 1955 (Box 22)
    - Watkins, Armatige, circa 1960 (Box 22)
    - Mrs. Whiton, circa 1905 (Box 22)
  - Recipes, undated (Box 22)
  - School records
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Barnard College, 1949 (Box 22)
    - Harvard University
      - Miscellaneous, 1910-1939 (Box 22)
      - Exams, 1911-1912 (Box 22)
      - Harvard Lampoon material, 1916 (Box 22)
      - Harvard Class Album, 1913 (Oversize 1)
    - Italian composition notebook, 1919 (Box 22)
    - M.I.T. Sloan Fellowship, 1945 (Box 22)
    - Morristown School
      - Reflections on life at Morristown School, 1908 (Box 22)
      - Morristonian, 1907-1909 (Box 22)
    - Sorbonne
      - Miscellaneous, 1918 (Box 22)
      - French composition notebooks, 1919 (Box 22)
      - French composition notebooks, 1919 (Box 23)
    - University of Vermont, 1949 (Box 23)
  - Scrapbooks, 1883-1939 (Box 23)
  - Scrapbooks, 1894-1964 (Oversize 1-5)
  - Songs, undated (Box 23)
- Organization records
  - American Society of Epicures, undated (Box 24)
  - Army-Air Force, undated (Box 24)
  - America First Committee, 1941 (Box 24)
  - American Garlic Society, 1948-1962 (Box 24)
    See also Correspondence: Incoming: Abb - Ame.
  - American Legion/Veterans Administration
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 24)
    - Digest of Minutes, 1932 (Box 24)
    - National Legislative Committee, 1932-1933 (Box 24)
    - Press Releases, 1932-1933 (Box 24)
  - Century Club
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1955 (Box 24)
    - Admissions Material, 1923-1954 (Box 24)
    - List of Members, undated (Box 24)
    - Memorial Correspondence, 1952-1967; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Obituaries, A-S, undated; 11 folders (Box 25)
    - Obituaries, T-Z, undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Programs, undated (Box 26)
    - Speeches and Addresses, 1953-1962 (Box 26)
  - Committee Against Privileged Classes, undated (Box 26)
  - Fight for Freedom, Inc., undated (Box 26)
  - Harris Institute, 1948 (Box 26)
  - Housatonic Valley Conference, 1941-1945 (Box 26)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, Inc., 1939 (Box 26)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1951 (Box 26)
  - New School for Social Research, 1939-1942 (Box 26)
  - New York School for Interior Design, 1962-1964 (Box 26)
  - Office of War Information, undated; miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Office of War Information, undated; clippings (Box 26)
  - Overseas Press Club, 1945-1961 (Box 26)
  - Saugatuck Valley Association, 1937-1951; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Sons of the Revolution, See Correspondence: Incoming: Sons of the Revolution.
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1960-1966 (Box 27)
  - Society of American Historians
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1961 (Box 27)
    - Milestones Magazine, 1949-1951; undated; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - U.S. Army